all right so once you know the titles of
the careers and the kinds of work that
exist that people can be paid for that
correspond with the tasks and activities
that you want to do every day now you
need to make uh a very short list of
employers that are doing those things
and this is not I want to be really
clear here this is not a list of
employers that you're going to apply for
today this is a list of employers and
and or organizations whatever that will
pay you money uh to do those jobs those
the places that have those jobs and I
want to be really clear on this point
the employers aren't all in Silicon
Valley and I'm not going to make a huge
ranty video about how much I hate Fang
companies all I'm going to say is that
most opportunities that you will find in
Tech are not in Silicon Valley and in
fact I would make the case that the
better opportunities are not in Silicon
Valley that the somewhat unsexy you know
jobs with with insurance agencies and
Banks and transportation companies and
Communications companies the things you
know the Bedrock of our of our you know
Society these jobs these very unsexy
jobs are out there and they pay very
well and they're not very well known so
when you're looking through for
employers and you're doing research and
you you can do your own research I don't
need to tell you where to go to do your
research right um um you can go out to
the internet there's indeed there's you
get do a search for you know employers
for whatever title and since you figured
out the title and the activities you can
now find out what those jobs are this is
not you're not looking for jobs okay
you're not yet looking for jobs what
you're looking for is what jobs exist
and what employers are specifically
employing for those jobs because it's
much much more important and I wish I
could zoom in on this it's much much
more important for you to find a company
culture that is compatible and a team
specifically a team of people who are
compatible with you as a human being
more than doing the thing that you want
to do every day because I mean it's at
least equally compatible obviously you
want to find something that's you know
what you want to do but you definitely
need to focus and I'm very fortunate I
I'm very fortunate to be on a team right
now um that I absolutely uh just admire
everybody on my team they are fourth
white communicators they're empathetic
they they are so intelligent and capable
uh they're open to being challenged I
mean it's all the things you really love
and that's largely because of the
employer and I can't talk about my
employer please don't ask but it has to
do with the employer now don't rule out
so some of the another thing I'll say
about employers is some of the big pay
companies like the Googles of the world
and Amazon they you might rule them out
because you're dis you disagree with
there something about the company and
that's your prerogative you can
certainly do that but I would just ask
you to consider the fact that some of
these companies are they're ultimately a
collection of people and the people in
them ultimately decide their Direction
so some of these companies you could
actually improve the company by working
for a company and then you know
operating within the company to make it
better and I'm going to cite the very
epic wonderful uh series Mr Robot and
the the plot line for Angela and the
plot line for Elliot um as they deal
with uh a corporation and how to change
a corporation from the in from within um
is a very very interesting exploration
um of of making change societal change
in some of these evil
corporations uh and and how you can go
about doing that so the point I'm making
is don't rule out evil corporations uh I
some of them I clearly I could never
ever work for them because they're so
evil um but they're you know most of the
time that doesn't mean that you have to
buy into everything that they do um but
you know it's going to be very hard for
you to find a company that you agree
with every single thing the company has
ever done so you're you're going to need
to you know allow for a little latitude
there uh you may find yourself in a
situation where you can you're you can
actually influence the company over time
so so don't rule those other employers
out um and that's it make sure you get a
good list and by the way when you get
the list done make it kind of a short
list and here's why and the last thing
I'm going to tell you to do here
um
well I'm GNA save this for another video